# Business Intelligence Analyst III ROBERT SMITH

Phone: (123) 456 78 99 Email: info@qwikresume.com Website: www.qwikresume.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/qwikresume Address: 1737 Marshville Road,

Alabama.

## **Objective**

I am a Business Intelligence Analyst Level III and a BO Universe Developer with over 10+ years of experience in the analysis, design, development, and maintenance of applications using Oracle and SAP Business Objects tools , RDBMS tools and designing universes, I have expertise in creating Info Spaces for SAP Business Explorer, and developing complex reports for financial analysis using Web Intelligence, BO Desktop, MS Excel, BO Analysis Tool, Live Office, and complex Oracle SQL queries.

## Skills

Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, Business Objects XI, R2/R3/R4 Development, BO Universes, IDT, BO Desktop, Web

## **Work Experience**

### **Business Intelligence Analyst III**

#### Automotive Resources International - April 2007 - Present

- To create new business objects (BO) universes on an ongoing basis and maintain about 120 existing BO universes.
- To interact with people at all levels, gather requirements and translate their business needs into technical requirements and then create universes according to their requirements.
- Assist the reporting group by developing complex and advanced level reports which the reporting group is not able to handle.
- Communicate with customers and managers of other departments to define business intelligence requirements and then lead initiatives to deliver solutions accordingly.
- To develop, document, and support the web based corporate reporting and troubleshoot existing bo reports.
- Incorporate complex logic through free hand SQL to implement complex business rules responsible for creation and maintenance of user accounts for about 2000 users in the absence of bo administrators.
- Successfully completed financial projects involving creation and automation of complicated financial reports to view ROI for all clients at a glance.

# **Reporting Analyst**

#### **GMAC Mortgage** - November 2005 - March 2007

- Responsibilities: maintained full responsibility for creating and managing bo universes that decreased the reporting time by 50% within multiple departments.
- In addition to designing and maintaining universes, I automated several reports using macros and programming skills, which resulted in reducing the time required for report generation by 75%.
- Previously a tedious function of report processing and generation was streamlined and was more accurate and efficient.
- Responsible for the data management and reporting for gm direct lending finance and strategic planning.
- Provide data processing and analytics support for financial administration.

- Designing and maintenance of financial, commission, and incentive databases.
- This is Dummy Description data, Replace with job description relevant to your current role. In case if you dont need it you can delete it.

## **Education**

MBA - 2008 to 2010(Daniels College Of Business, University Of Denver ) B.Tech 2001 to 2005 (Delhi University - Delhi, Delhi )